<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Understanding Others &#8211; ELEVAROS</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/understanding-others/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:20:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i2.wp.com/elevaros.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cropped-ElevarosSiteImage-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Understanding Others &#8211; ELEVAROS</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">163234309</site>	<item>
		<title>A Powerful Mindset Shift: &#8220;Everyone is Doing Their Best&#8221;</title>
		<link>/everyone-is-doing-their-best/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you want to be more helpful and have more impact in your conversations? A friend of mine,&#160;Caroline&#160;asked an important question:&#160; &#8220;Do you think most people are doing the best job they can?&#8221; I responded: &#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter if they are or not. But if I treat every interaction with the mindset that others ARE [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/everyone-is-doing-their-best/">A Powerful Mindset Shift: &#8220;Everyone is Doing Their Best&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Do you want to be more helpful and have more impact in your conversations?</p>



<p>A friend of mine,&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://yourglobalfamily.com/who-we-are" rel="noreferrer noopener">Caroline</a>&nbsp;asked an important question:&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>&#8220;Do you think most people are doing the best job they can?&#8221;</em></p>



<p>I responded:</p>



<p><em>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter if they are or not. But if I treat every interaction with the mindset that others ARE doing their best, MY best comes out. I am more empathetic, more accommodating, and I&#8217;m in a place where I can serve them better.&#8221;</em></p>



<p>It is easy to forget that you control how you respond to others. I have forgotten this over and over in life, and it&#8217;s something I need to be reminded of often.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Who can you apply this mindset to and improve your relationship? It could be a coworker, a family member, or maybe both!</p>



<p>I&#8217;d love to hear from you &#8211; <a href="mailto:ken@elevaros.com">email me</a> here!</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/everyone-is-doing-their-best/">A Powerful Mindset Shift: &#8220;Everyone is Doing Their Best&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Magic of Seeing Others</title>
		<link>/the-magic-of-seeing-others/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It doesn&#8217;t have to be massive effort &#8211; it just takes a small gesture. In a very short timeframe, the world has changed. But you have the power to help make this easier to navigate. Yes, you. You have the power to create magic. We are in this thing together. If we connect with our [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-magic-of-seeing-others/">The Magic of Seeing Others</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It doesn&#8217;t have to be massive effort &#8211; it just takes a small gesture.</p>



<p>In a very short timeframe, the world has changed. But you have the power to help make this easier to navigate.</p>



<p><em>Yes, you.</em><strong> </strong><strong>You have the power to create magic</strong>.</p>



<p>We are in this thing together. If we connect with our friends, our families, acquaintances, and even those that we don&#8217;t know (in safe, social distancing ways), we see hope.</p>



<p>This week, I&#8217;ve reached out to several people (via text, phone calls, video, and email) to see how they were doing. And it has been amazing &#8211; people are genuinely grateful to be seen.</p>



<p>Seth Godin in his May 4, 2014&nbsp;<a href="https://seths.blog/2014/05/to-be-seen/">blog post</a>&nbsp;wrote, &#8220;When we offer people a chance to matter and to be seen, we have the chance to offer them something magical.&#8221;</p>



<p>So get out there and &#8220;see&#8221; others. And watch the magic happen.</p>



<p>It is just that simple.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Want more articles like this BEFORE they are published to the web?<br> Signup for the weekly Elevaros Newsletter</em><br> </p>


<div class='_form_13'></div><script type='text/javascript' src='https://kbconsulting.activehosted.com/f/embed.php?static=0&id=13&614CDFD0076A1&nostyles=0&preview=0'></script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-magic-of-seeing-others/">The Magic of Seeing Others</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1337</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Assess Your Value</title>
		<link>/how-to-assess-your-value/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week I had an interesting conversation about value. The person I was coaching said, “I didn’t really do anything yesterday &#8211; I was a real piece of s**t.” And something really important clicked for me. There’s a huge difference between your economic value (what you output and give to society) and your inherent value [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-assess-your-value/">How to Assess Your Value</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This week I had an interesting conversation about value. </p>



<p>The person I was coaching said, “I didn’t really do anything yesterday &#8211; I was a real piece of s**t.” And something really important clicked for me. </p>



<p>There’s a huge difference between your economic value (what you output and give to society) and your inherent value as a human being. </p>



<p>I have been guilty of this for many years and still struggle with it. But a new way of thinking about people and their value can help you be a better human.</p>



<p>We often think of how valuable a person is by their economic value. How much do they make? How advanced is their career? How many things have they accrued? How nice are their cars? </p>



<p>But none of this matters to the inherent value of another human being. </p>



<p>I’ve had to fire people in the past for bringing down a team and not doing the work they were assigned to do. But that absolutely doesn’t mean that the person getting fired was less valuable. Yes, it’s true, they were no longer economically viable to keep on the payroll &#8211; but that fact DOES NOT diminish their value as a human one iota. </p>



<p>You can see it often &#8211; picture the person yelling, “Get a job!” to a homeless person asking for money on the street corner. Their misplaced value of that person says they are less than because they have less than others. </p>



<p>You see it when a person in the workplace is disrespectful to the janitor or the security guard or the delivery person. </p>



<p>Every one &#8211; EVERY PERSON &#8211; has immense value. And even if they can do nothing for you &#8211; that doesn’t diminish it at all. </p>



<p>This mindset shift is important &#8211; it will help you understand to be more compassionate with others. It will help you not be so frustrated the next time the panhandler asks you for money. It will help you transform the way you think about yourself too. </p>



<p>You are not your career &#8211; no matter how successful you are. That didn’t increase your inherent value at all. Sure, your bank account might have more than most people around you, but that does not mean you’re better than any of them.</p>



<p>Even if you’re great to those around you and see the inherent value in every human &#8211; I bet you’re not that way with yourself all the time. </p>



<p>It’s sneaky and insidious &#8211; you feel bad after an unproductive day. You forgot to run an errand &#8211; so you internally call yourself a name. You missed a key deadline at work &#8211; you call yourself a lazy son-of-a-… you get the picture. </p>



<p>You are valuable.<br>Treat yourself as such. </p>



<p>When you separate your economic value from your inherent value, you’ll be transformed into someone you might not even recognize. And others will see it too. </p>



<p>And the big surprise is, when you separate your work output from your value as a human being, you are freed up to get more done and create more economic </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Want more articles like this&nbsp;BEFORE&nbsp;they are published to the web?<br> Signup for the weekly Elevaros Newsletter</em><br> </p>


<div class='_form_13'></div><script type='text/javascript' src='https://kbconsulting.activehosted.com/f/embed.php?static=0&id=13&614CDFD00994B&nostyles=0&preview=0'></script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-assess-your-value/">How to Assess Your Value</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1265</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Good Metrics Don&#8217;t Always Equal Success</title>
		<link>/why-good-metrics-dont-always-equal-success/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I love cake, don’t you? There was a cake at the big meeting, so you know it was a happy time. Our company had just completed a year-long initiative to implement ITIL &#8211; a process improvement effort to make IT more efficient. We were celebrating the completion of a ton of work- this was tough [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-good-metrics-dont-always-equal-success/">Why Good Metrics Don&#8217;t Always Equal Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I love cake, don’t you?</p>



<p>There was a cake at the big meeting, so you know it was a happy time.</p>



<p>Our company had just completed a year-long initiative to implement ITIL &#8211; a process improvement effort to make IT more efficient. We were celebrating the completion of a ton of work- this was tough for such a big organization.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, there is an unwritten rule in Corporate America that you must have PowerPoint BEFORE cake. Sigh.</p>



<p>I watched the presentation holding back my thoughts about what kind of cake I was about to enjoy.</p>



<p>The “big win” we were celebrating was the reduction in the number of service tickets &#8211; a 25% drop in the number of calls and emails into the service desk reporting problems. </p>



<p>25% was even written on the cake in sloppy blue icing.</p>



<p>“Yay! Fewer issues &#8211; we’re amazing!”</p>



<p>But even as I took a bite of my slice of cake &#8211; a white cake with a raspberry filling &#8211; I knew we <em>shouldn’t</em> be celebrating that particular number. </p>



<p>The truth of the matter was the big number we were all supposed to be excited about was the opposite of what we thought we’d get. </p>



<p>From a few conversations with customers, as a result of the new processes and procedures we put in place &#8211; our service desk got MORE DIFFICULT to work with. They were figuring out ways to fix things WITHOUT having to call the service desk.</p>



<p>As we became less effective, people called less and less. </p>



<p>That’s not really an occasion for cake. </p>



<p>That’s the danger of metrics &#8211; if they are incomplete &#8211; they can be misleading. </p>



<p>Metrics are not bad &#8211; but relying solely on them as a barometer to gauge success (or not) is not wise. No set of KPIs fully encompasses a customer&#8217;s experience. </p>



<p>Be careful when designing metrics for your organization &#8211; if you depend on them as the only source of truth, you can be deceived. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-good-metrics-dont-always-equal-success/">Why Good Metrics Don&#8217;t Always Equal Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1261</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Keys to Giving Effective Presentations</title>
		<link>/three-keys-to-giving-effective-presentations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>All technologists need presentation skills, whether you’re presenting to one person or to many. As such, here are three tips that I’ve found particularly useful that can help you get your message across. What is the cognitive effect I want my audience to experience? Often times, we forget the audience when we’re developing our presentations. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/three-keys-to-giving-effective-presentations/">Three Keys to Giving Effective Presentations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>All technologists need presentation skills, whether you’re presenting to one person or to many. As such, here are three tips that I’ve found particularly useful that can help you get your message across.</p>



<p><strong>What is the cognitive effect I want my audience to experience?</strong></p>



<p>Often times, we forget the audience when we’re developing our presentations. It is easy to focus on our subject and just dive right into the content — and hope people catch on. But it is helpful to think about the effect you want your presentation to have BEFORE you start building it. </p>



<p>For example, if you were asked to give a talk on a new technology your team is looking to use, your cognitive effect could either be “to get the team excited about it” or “to teach the team to operate it.” Do you see how those would be wildly different presentations on the same subject? </p>



<p>Knowing your intended effect even before creating your presentation is a great strategy. But don’t leave it only as an initial step. Continually review and ensure that your presentation is meeting this important goal throughout the development of your talk.</p>



<p><strong>Get comfortable with silence</strong></p>



<p>I spent a couple of years in a Toastmasters club, and one of the most important takeaways is that silence is a key part of any presentation.</p>



<p>Most new speakers have an aversion to silence, though. After all, the point of a presentation is to talk, right? So we react and try to fill all of the available time with words. </p>



<p>But silence does a lot of important things: 1) it allows your audience to process what you’ve said, 2) it can be leveraged to create tension and drama for an emotional connection, and 3) it shows your audience that you are at ease, even if you feel like vomiting or passing out. </p>



<p><strong>The power of &#8220;Thank You&#8221; and &#8220;I’ll Get Back to You On That&#8221;</strong></p>



<p>One of the most challenging things that can happen during a presentation is when one of your audience members gives you some feedback or asks a challenging question you don’t know the answer to right away.</p>



<p>In the first scenario, if someone speaks up to tell you that you had an error in your presentation — whether or not they are correct — don’t try to argue or defend your point. Just say, “Thank you,” earnestly and sincerely and move on.</p>



<p>Similarly, if an attendee asks you a question that you don’t know the answer to immediately, it’s completely fine in most circumstances to say, “I don’t have that right now, but I’ll get back to you on that.” And after the presentation concludes, follow up with the questioner. This way, you avoid getting derailed and stay in control. But you are also genuinely helpful. None of us knows everything, so it is completely acceptable to say, “I’ll get back to you on that,” and follow through afterward. But danger! Saying you’ll follow up and then never following through is a credibility killer. If you say you will do something, then do everything in your power to do it. I like to have a notebook handy. And as soon as my presentation is over, I write down my takeaways right away so that I don’t forget them later. In other words, do what works for you.</p>



<p>Practice these the next time you give a presentation, and I’m sure you’ll get your message across more effectively.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Want more articles like this&nbsp;BEFORE&nbsp;they are published to the web?<br> Signup for the weekly Elevaros Newsletter</em><br> </p>


<div class='_form_13'></div><script type='text/javascript' src='https://kbconsulting.activehosted.com/f/embed.php?static=0&id=13&614CDFD00D86D&nostyles=0&preview=0'></script>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/three-keys-to-giving-effective-presentations/">Three Keys to Giving Effective Presentations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">846</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Meaning of Sonder</title>
		<link>/the-meaning-of-sonder/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 02:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Often we get stuck in our own world and think others are experiencing something the same way we are.&#160; But often, it is not the case at all. There&#8217;s a new-ish word out there that explains it somewhat: &#8216;Sonder.&#8217; I&#8217;m paraphrasing here, but &#8216;Sonder&#8217; is the realization that others around you are living a life [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-meaning-of-sonder/">The Meaning of Sonder</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Often we get stuck in our own world and think others are experiencing something the same way we are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But often, it is not the case at all.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a new-ish word out there that explains it somewhat: &#8216;Sonder.&#8217; I&#8217;m paraphrasing here, but &#8216;Sonder&#8217; is the realization that others around you are living a life that is as complex and as colorful as yours is, with all kinds of ups and downs, celebrations and disappointments, happy and sad times.</p>



<p>When you reflect on this and start to get it, your view of the world changes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You understand that people want to be acknowledged by you and by others. When people are heard, they are at their best &#8211; and they feel valued.</p>



<p>A technologist needs to realize that not everyone &#8211; not your customers, not your manager, not even your closest friends have the same experience. This concept seems obvious, but it is something I have taken for granted.</p>



<p>Two people can watch a movie, and one can hate it, and the other person can love it. Wasn&#8217;t it the same movie?&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re all evaluating, judging, and filtering all inputs based on our own experiences, and we filter things we observe through these lenses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When we say something to a coworker &#8211; and they look at you with a furled eyebrow &#8211; you didn&#8217;t mean to offend them, but obviously, your words didn&#8217;t come across as you intended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8216;Sonder&#8217; can help us understand others. Everyone&#8217;s own &#8216;movie&#8217; is playing along in their heads. And your words filtered through their experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do we solve the problem of our intention not matching how our message was received? First, we listen and observe the reaction to our words. Listening after we speak is vital &#8211; most of the time, we let words fly and never check to see how they landed. When we see that the words didn&#8217;t land the way we intended, we can apologize. A quick, &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry, I think that came across wrong&#8221; can help immensely. And then, if the timing is right, try again with different word choices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Being in tune with those we communicate is difficult &#8211; but it is most definitely a learned skill. We can all improve upon it. I have to work at it every day.</p>



<p>But knowing about &#8216;Sonder&#8217;: that every person you&#8217;ll ever encounter has a rich &#8220;movie&#8221; playing along in their world, the better you&#8217;ll know to be on the watch &#8211; watching out for when your words fall outside what you intended. When you&#8217;re in tune with this, people will understand you better.</p>



<p><strong><a href="/">Click here to get </a></strong><em><strong><a href="/">The Elevaros Dispatch</a></strong></em><strong><a href="/">, a weekly newsletter written by technologists, for technologists to help you elevate your tech expertise</a></strong><a href="/">.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-meaning-of-sonder/">The Meaning of Sonder</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">812</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;We&#8217; and &#8216;They&#8217;: Expand Your &#8216;We&#8217; and Watch Your Career Accelerate</title>
		<link>/we-and-they/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 02:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m reading the book,&#160;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind. Author Dr. Yuval Noah Harari writes, &#8220;Sapiens instinctively divide humanity into two parts, &#8216;we&#8217; and &#8216;they&#8217;.&#8221;The concepts of &#8220;we&#8221; and &#8220;they&#8221; have powerful implications for your success. For most of my career, I maintained a very small &#8220;we.&#8221; Only a few select people were part of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/we-and-they/">&#8216;We&#8217; and &#8216;They&#8217;: Expand Your &#8216;We&#8217; and Watch Your Career Accelerate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I&#8217;m reading the book,&nbsp;<em>Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</em>. Author Dr. Yuval Noah Harari writes, &#8220;Sapiens instinctively divide humanity into two parts, &#8216;we&#8217; and &#8216;they&#8217;.&#8221;<br><strong><br>The concepts of &#8220;we&#8221; and &#8220;they&#8221; have powerful implications for your success.</strong></p>



<p>For most of my career, I maintained a very small &#8220;we.&#8221; Only a few select people were part of my &#8220;we&#8221;— everyone else was a &#8220;they.&#8221; That was a limiting belief that hindered my career.</p>



<p><strong>Do you have this same limiting belief?&nbsp;</strong>If you want to keep your group small and never push beyond that, you&#8217;ll struggle to find abundance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve classified yourself and a few coworkers as &#8220;we&#8221; and everyone else as &#8220;they.&#8221;   Why? What good does that do anyone?</p>



<p>If you work at a large organization you likely have a corporate mission statement and a set of shared values. You might dismiss them as just window dressing— but think about them and how you fit into the equation. Even if you don&#8217;t resonate with the mission and vision, you&#8217;re a part of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do you want to try to accomplish that mission with just a few people or do you want the entire organization to pursue it? Which scenario would be less frustrating?&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Actively work to expand your &#8220;we&#8221; and you&#8217;ll see your career grow exponentially.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Do you want to find the kind of connection that boosts your happiness and satisfaction with life? Do you want to find your next job before you need it? Do you want to make a big difference in others&#8217; lives? Then change your definition of &#8220;we&#8221; to include more people.</p>



<p>Accepting more people into your definition of &#8220;we&#8221; is how you will escape the crush of what feels to be a dead-end job— you connect with more than just yourself. Your tasks and responsibilities become more and more critical. You see your value in the organization and how your work (no matter how minute you perceived it to be in the past) impacts the overall goals of your organization.</p>



<p><strong>Even if you have a great department and you truly consider all of your technology teammates as &#8220;we&#8221;, why do you think of other departments in the same organization as &#8220;they&#8221;?</strong></p>



<p>&#8220;They caused this issue,&#8221; and &#8220;they are being totally unreasonable,&#8221; are things I heard regularly in the corporate world. But these folks are all working for the same organization! Why fight each other? It&#8217;s madness that we&#8217;ve all succumbed to occasionally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I think about getting together with a team I had several years ago I see how those &#8220;us versus them&#8221; walls have broken down. Those factions don&#8217;t matter much now— and looking back on them they didn&#8217;t mean much then either. It was all unnecessary noise that distracted us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Keeping your &#8220;we&#8221; small is human nature— but humanity has evolved by breaking free of primal tendencies; so, resist the urge to stay small.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I encourage you to expand your &#8220;we.&#8221; When you do, you will see greater success and personal fulfillment.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Who could you add to your &#8220;we&#8221; group today?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>I&#8217;d love to hear from you as you expand your &#8220;we&#8221;. Please <a href="mailto:ken@elevaros.com">email me</a> with your stories big or small.</em></p>


<p style="text-align: center;"><script src="//static.leadpages.net/leadboxes/current/embed.js" async="" defer=""></script> <button style="background: #3a00db; border-color: #3a00db; border-radius: 14px; color: #ffffff; display: inline-block; vertical-align: middle; padding: 16px 32px; min-width: 192px; border: 1px solid #3a00db; font-size: 1rem; font-family: Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: center; outline: 0; line-height: 1; cursor: pointer; -webkit-transition: background 0.3s, color 0.3s, border 0.3s; transition: background 0.3s, color 0.3s, border 0.3s; box-shadow: 0px 1px 5px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.6);" data-leadbox-popup="6gJvShxuourJ2KLEZyUsM7" data-leadbox-domain="elevaros.lpages.co">Want More? </button></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/we-and-they/">&#8216;We&#8217; and &#8216;They&#8217;: Expand Your &#8216;We&#8217; and Watch Your Career Accelerate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">781</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hard Truth About Your Team&#8217;s Culture</title>
		<link>/the-hard-truth-about-your-teams-culture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 18:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=778</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the book, All In, authors Adrian Gostick and Chester Elton focus on how managers create great places to work. The subtitle of the book is, &#8220;How the best managers create a culture of belief and drive big results.&#8221; If you&#8217;re a manager or director &#8211; I recommend it. But the hard truth is that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-hard-truth-about-your-teams-culture/">The Hard Truth About Your Team&#8217;s Culture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the book, <em>All In</em>, authors Adrian Gostick and Chester Elton focus on how managers create great places to work. The subtitle of the book is, &#8220;How the best managers create a culture of belief and drive big results.&#8221; If you&#8217;re a manager or director &#8211; I recommend it.</p>



<p>But the hard truth is that great cultures DON&#8217;T ONLY come from great managers: </p>



<p style="text-align:center"><strong>Great Team Members Create the BEST Cultures.</strong></p>



<p>Early in my career, I waited around for an excellent manager to help make our team better. I had bad or even mediocre managers and complained that they weren&#8217;t creating a healthy working environment instead of doing something to improve it myself.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s right &#8211; YOU have the power (and the responsibility!) to make your work environment the best you can make it.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s the classic mix-up between management and leadership. We expect our managers to be good leaders too &#8211; and when they don&#8217;t lead well, the tendency is to sit back and complain.</p>



<p>But we can (and should!) be leaders &#8211; and we don&#8217;t have to have an official role or title to lead.</p>



<p>You can be a leader &#8211; even if you don&#8217;t think you&#8217;re a good one &#8211; by modeling what you want to see in your team. If you want a better culture of sharing information and knowledge, share what you know with those around you. If you want an environment of shared responsibility instead of always playing the blame game, be a model for everyone else. If you want a culture of openness and welcoming to all &#8211; model it! And when you see people aren&#8217;t doing those behaviors, tactfully point out better ways to handle it. </p>



<p>You have a responsibility to your co-workers to model behavior that leads to more openness, sharing, and ultimately a more effective team. There&#8217;s no more room for shaming other&#8217;s mistakes, for excluding others that &#8220;aren&#8217;t in our club,&#8221; and for negativity. If you see something wrong, work to make it right &#8211; don&#8217;t add fuel to the fire by complaining and not doing anything to help. </p>



<p>There are plenty of people (I know you&#8217;ve met them) that feed off of negativity. Don&#8217;t feed those monsters &#8211; hitting them with positivity and a positive outlook is how you turn that around. It won&#8217;t happen overnight, but it certainly can happen if you persist.</p>



<p style="text-align:center"><strong>You Don&#8217;t Need a Formal Title to Lead.</strong></p>



<p>I&#8217;ve seen some of the most junior staff members lead teams in ways that improve the group significantly. I&#8217;ve also seen very senior members drag the whole group down with dangerous negativity.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t wait around for your manager, director, or other appointed managerial representative to make your culture the way you want it. Seek it out, model it, praise those that are making it better and call out destructive behaviors, and you&#8217;ll create the environment where you love to work. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-medium-font-size"><br><em><strong> If you&#8217;re looking for a big boost of your own leadership skills or improving your team&#8217;s dynamics, I can help!</strong></em></p>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>I fast-track your improvement through one-on-one coaching, team workshops, and online training. What will be best for your situation? Let&#8217;s find out!</strong></p>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-medium-font-size"><strong><a href="mailto:ken@elevaros.com">Email me </a>and let me know your biggest challenge.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-hard-truth-about-your-teams-culture/">The Hard Truth About Your Team&#8217;s Culture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">778</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meetings, Meetings, and More Meetings: When Will I Ever Get Any Work Done?</title>
		<link>/meetings-meetings-and-more-meetings-when-will-i-ever-get-any-work-done/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 22:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; I have yet to meet a technologist that believes that going to meetings is the best thing about their job. In fact, most technologists hate meetings. Unfortunately, I don’t have a magic pill that eliminates them all, but I do have some strategies to reduce them. Why do we have meetings? At their simplest, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/meetings-meetings-and-more-meetings-when-will-i-ever-get-any-work-done/">Meetings, Meetings, and More Meetings: When Will I Ever Get Any Work Done?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span class="">I have yet to meet a technologist that believes that going to meetings is the best thing about their job.</span></p>
<p><span class="">In fact, most technologists hate meetings.</span></p>
<p>Unfortunately, I don’t have a magic pill that eliminates them all, but I do have some strategies to reduce them.</p>
<p>Why do we have meetings? At their simplest, meetings help us connect to shared objectives, they serve to work out hidden dependencies we may not have thought about, and they help get all of the meeting attendees (hopefully!) on the same page. Why is that bad? Those all sound like things we all want, so why do we hate meetings so much?</p>
<p>Business author Patrick Lencioni wrote in his book &#8220;Death by Meeting&#8221; that meetings were &#8220;…the most painful problem in business.&#8221; It is not just techs that are frustrated and fed-up with meetings: it is a feeling across all sections of organizations.</p>
<p>If everyone hates them, why are they so pervasive? Some days as an internal corporate IT staffer, all I did some days was go from meeting to meeting to meeting and never had the opportunity to get any actual work done.</p>
<p>But in the face of all that negativity, there are some things that you can do to reduce the number of meetings in your life.</p>
<p>One of the biggest sources of high-frequency meetings are project managers of initiatives we are assigned to work. At any one time, you might be tasked to work on more than a dozen projects. And most of them will have a different project manager. That is a LOT of meetings. (as a consultant, I often work on one project at a time, and after years of multi-project juggling it almost feels like a break!) Is it possible to reduce the number of meetings you have in this scenario? YES!</p>
<p>The majority of meetings that a project manager will schedule are status meetings. Status meetings are important because this is where the project manager gets the latest and greatest update on the project they are held responsible. I have several friends that are project managers &#8211; their job is stressful. Often, they are given (in my opinion) a disproportionate amount of responsibility for the delivery of a project and very little authority. Who gets blamed if that project doesn’t run well? The project manager. Who gets the blame if it goes over budget? The project manager. Who gets the blame if the technical people don’t get their tasks done and they make the project late? The project manager. That is a tough place to live every day! So, thinking about the project manager and the frustrating place they live, with little authority but a ton of responsibility, why do you think they conduct so many meetings?</p>
<p>I know, I know: some of you still think project managers have a secret desire to torture us with as many meetings as possible. But it’s really not true: they hold all of these meetings because they HAVE to stay connected to the pulse of a project or they risk having a project escape their control and turn into an abysmal failure. So, close your eyes. Seriously, this will help. Close your eyes and picture yourself being told by the CEO that YOU, and you alone, are responsible for the delivery of a project you’re currently working on. Think about what you know about what the other vital team members are working on and their current status. Is your mind pretty blank? You don’t know? Well in that case, how could you get that information? You could email them, but you won’t get the whole story and maybe you might not get a response at all from some of them. The acid in your stomach starts to move up your esophagus, and you think, &#8220;I better just call a meeting first thing tomorrow morning so I can get that status from all involved.&#8221; BOOM &#8211; now you see why so many meetings are called by project managers.</p>
<p>So, have you figured it out? The key to getting fewer meeting requests is to reduce the number of unknowns you’re floating out there! One of the most over-used phrases is (and yes, I find it quite ironic) the advice to &#8220;over-communicate.&#8221; The problem is with that advice is there really is no realistic way to over-communicate. I have never met someone that ever over-communicated anything. Sure, there have been many people that are guilty of TMI &#8211; sharing Too Much Information &#8211; but none that have ever over communicated.</p>
<p>I have seen technologists successfully navigate their way to fewer meetings. And the way they do that is to communicate their status on projects to all concerned continually. That is only nine words, ’communicate their status on projects to all concerned continually,’ but they are incredibly powerful. I can’t tell you how much people who have a stake in your work that you do will appreciate you if you adopt this rule. Your manager will love it, the project managers of every project you’re involved in (even tangentially) will adore you, and your customers will rave about your abilities to accomplish great things.</p>
<h4>Want more articles like this BEFORE they are published to the web?<br />
Signup for the weekly Elevaros Newsletter<br />
<div class='_form_13'></div><script type='text/javascript' src='https://kbconsulting.activehosted.com/f/embed.php?static=0&id=13&614CDFD01B1DC&nostyles=0&preview=0'></script></h4>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/meetings-meetings-and-more-meetings-when-will-i-ever-get-any-work-done/">Meetings, Meetings, and More Meetings: When Will I Ever Get Any Work Done?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">449</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;You Will Gain&#8221;: An Easy Way to Focus Your Efforts</title>
		<link>/you-will-gain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 23:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; As a teenager, I really wanted to work at a bike shop, but I was running into dead ends. Over and over, I would travel to my favorite shops and apply, only to receive no callbacks. I was just another job applicant with minimal experience. I was frustrated. But then I read the book [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/you-will-gain/">&#8220;You Will Gain&#8221;: An Easy Way to Focus Your Efforts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a teenager, I really wanted to work at a bike shop, but I was running into dead ends. Over and over, I would travel to my favorite shops and apply, only to receive no callbacks. I was just another job applicant with minimal experience. I was frustrated.</p>
<p>But then I read the book <em>How to Get the Job You Really Want</em> by Joe Sabah. Joe encouraged the job seeker not just to fill out applications and send resumes, but to send an alternative: the Gold Form.</p>
<p>The Gold Form flipped a job search on its head. Printed on goldenrod colored paper for its high contrast to black and also to differentiate it from all the other white paper in the world, it started with the words WANTED: at the top and then described what the job seeker was hunting. Mine said something like WANTED: Professional Bike Shop Seeking a Repair Tech.</p>
<p>It listed, in short bullet point phrases, all of the attributes of a great bike shop. About halfway down the page were the words, YOU WILL GAIN.</p>
<p>Below that, I listed all the great attributes I had: customer service oriented, hard worker, diligent repair tech, etc. These were attributes that were known to be an asset to the bike shop owner. Of course, they would want an employee like me.</p>
<p>At the bottom of the Gold Form, I finished with, &#8220;Easily solve your Bike Repair Tech needs and call Ken today&#8221; and listed my phone number.</p>
<p>I sent them out to all of the bike shops in Denver within the radius of where I was willing to commute. Within a week I had the job I wanted. I think stamps cost a quarter then, and the total cost of the paper and copies were less than 15 bucks &#8211; a great return on investment.</p>
<p>So what does all this have to do with technology services? If you think about the words on the Gold Form, YOU WILL GAIN, and have an answer for every project you work on; you will be much more effective. This will help you keep in mind what is most important. The only reason to do these projects is for gain, so take the time to define what the benefit is before you start. Just as the only reason for a bike shop owner to hire me was for the gain they would get from me working there, the only reason to do IT projects is for the gains they bring our customers.</p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t know how your customers will gain from your efforts, you are heading into the dangerous territory of spinning your wheels for no reason. Make your work more meaningful and impactful by having an answer to YOU WILL GAIN on every project you work.</p>
<h4>Want more articles like this BEFORE they are published to the web?<br />
Signup for the weekly Elevaros Newsletter<br />
<div class='_form_13'></div><script type='text/javascript' src='https://kbconsulting.activehosted.com/f/embed.php?static=0&id=13&614CDFD01BD6C&nostyles=0&preview=0'></script></h4>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/you-will-gain/">&#8220;You Will Gain&#8221;: An Easy Way to Focus Your Efforts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ELEVAROS</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">390</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
