<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Self-Management &#8211; ELEVAROS</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/self-management/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 22:08:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i2.wp.com/elevaros.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cropped-ElevarosSiteImage-2.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Self-Management &#8211; ELEVAROS</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">163234309</site>	<item>
		<title>Getting Clear on What You Want</title>
		<link>/getting-clear-on-what-you-want/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 03:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Whatcha, whatcha, whatcha want?” -Beastie Boys&#160; How well have you defined what you want out of your career and your life? When I ask my coaching clients this question, most answer confidently that they are clear. Then the obvious follow-up question hits: “So what do you want?”&#160; And when they try to articulate what it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>“Whatcha, whatcha, whatcha want?” -Beastie Boys&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>How well have you defined what you want out of your career and your life?</p>



<p>When I ask my coaching clients this question, most answer confidently that they are clear.</p>



<p>Then the obvious follow-up question hits: “So what do you want?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when they try to articulate what it is they want, most find that it is a struggle to get it out in a clear way.</p>



<p>What seems like an easy question to answer on the surface, turns out to be pretty difficult in practice.</p>



<p>Why is that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve seen two primary reasons that people are unclear about their hopes and dreams. And both reasons center around fear.</p>



<p>First off, if you know deep down what it is you want out of life, it is difficult to tell another person this information. You begin to filter out your true desires and try to put the best spin on it. It is natural to not want judgment from others. You don’t want to seem selfish. Yet talking about your innermost hopes and dreams is selfish- and it’s okay! Selfishness is not always bad.</p>



<p>The second way fear shows up when talking about dreams and goals is in the fear of disappointment. Some can’t stand the thought of disappointing others if they don’t achieve the audacious goal they set. But most often, it is the fear of disappointing yourself. It feels safe to avoid big goals &#8211; and dangerous to say them out loud. I believe this is the biggest one that keeps people from achieving the life they want.</p>



<p><em>Are you letting fear keep you from achieving your biggest goals? </em></p>



<p><strong>Take a few minutes today to write out what it is you want.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Don’t put limitations on yourself &#8211; give yourself permission to dream.</p>



<p>And when fear creeps up, keep writing. Combat the fear by being 100% honest with yourself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then you’ll know just how clear you are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1328</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Difference Between &#8216;BEST&#8217; and  &#8216;EFFECTIVE&#8217;</title>
		<link>/the-difference-between-best-and-effective/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do you think the difference is between the BEST tech staffer and the most EFFECTIVE? Over the past couple of years, I have experimented with a simple question. I ask technologists, “What are the attributes of the BEST tech staff?” I usually get statements about the most technically astute person they know. They tell [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>What do you think the difference is between the BEST tech staffer and the most EFFECTIVE? </p>



<p>Over the past couple of years, I have experimented with a simple question. I ask technologists, “What are the attributes of the BEST tech staff?” I usually get statements about the most technically astute person they know. They tell me about someone that knows all the ins and outs of a particular technology. </p>



<p>When I change the question a bit, the answers change dramatically. Asking, “What are the attributes of the most EFFECTIVE tech staffer?” invariably I get a lot more. I hear, &#8220;customer skills, communication, a bias towards action, someone that gets a lot done with competence.&#8221; </p>



<p>When I&#8217;ve gone further with people and asked them to put a name to the BEST versus EFFECTIVE, in most cases they mention two different people. </p>



<p>Technologists generally think that to get ahead we need to get more and more technical skills. </p>



<p>That’s only true if you’re not concerned with being effective! Of course, we need to be competent technically, but not exclusively.</p>



<p>Once you have a base technical knowledge, it is easy to build upon it. But at some point there are diminishing returns &#8211; more tech knowledge doesn’t increase your ability to deliver.</p>



<p>It’s about communication, building rapport, managing your commitments, and so many other things. Don’t get me wrong- you’ve still got to have technical ability but if you’ve been in tech for any length of time you likely have a solid foundation.</p>



<p>What are you doing to boost your effectiveness? What are the things that are limiting you from becoming more effective? </p>



<p>I’d love to hear what you’re doing to become more effective. What are the small things you’re doing? What could you improve upon? </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Get Anything You Want</title>
		<link>/how-to-get-anything-you-want/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For many years of my life, there was a dull hum in the background of my inner monologue. It wasn’t loud, but it was powerful. I wasn’t even conscious of it most of the time, but my actions and daily decisions were guided by it.&#160; What I realize now, is that there was a voice [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For many years of my life, there was a dull hum in the background of my inner monologue. It wasn’t loud, but it was powerful. I wasn’t even conscious of it most of the time, but my actions and daily decisions were guided by it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I realize now, is that there was a voice inside of me that said,&nbsp;<em>“You can’t do that. You don’t measure up. Look at how successful those around you are. You’ll never be as good as that.”&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Even though it was background noise, it had a negative effect on my life. It kept me from taking more risks, it held me back from doing everything I could to make my dreams a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I started a business in the mid-2000s, that ugly voice pre-destined that it wasn’t going to work out. It told me that I wasn’t enough to make it happen.</p>



<p><strong>NONE OF THAT WAS TRUE.</strong>&nbsp;But that business failure came into being anyway because my mindset ensured that was going to be the result. My business failed and for several years I blamed external things. It was the economy, it was the market I was trying to jump into, it was other people letting me down. But that wasn’t true either &#8211; at its core, it was my mindset that determined the outcome. That “not good enough” mindset kept me from doing the exact things I needed to do to get success. It told me that it wasn’t going to happen no matter how hard I worked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It seems mystical and fluffy &#8211; but it is as real as anything you can hold in your hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The words we use to talk to ourselves are the most important words in the universe.</p>



<p>Henry Ford said,&nbsp;<em>“Whether you think you can, or you think you can&#8217;t&#8211;you&#8217;re right.”&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Your mindset determines your outcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Having a mindset that communicates to your innermost fiber that says&nbsp;<em>“You can do it &#8211; you can persevere &#8211; you can have anything you want”</em>&nbsp;is extremely powerful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That doesn’t mean you won’t have to overcome adversity. Or that everything will be easy. Nope &#8211; that’s not true at all. But when you maintain a mindset that you are powerful and that you can persevere in the face of challenges, then you’re on the path to a great achievement. It might not happen when you want or how you’ve planned it all out, but with an unbreakable mindset, you can achieve anything. Really &#8211; anything!</p>



<p>What are the things your inner monologue is telling you right now? Are they positive words or are they dragging you down?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Take the time to listen to them &#8211; no matter how quiet or loud they are. Decide right now to make a habit that when you tell yourself something negative, you replace it with something positive. The more you replace negativity with empowering words, the more you will produce positive results in your life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today can be the day it all turns around. And it starts with you deciding you’re good enough as you are.<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fear and the Art of Redirection</title>
		<link>/fear-and-the-art-of-redirection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 15:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learn to Conquer Redirect Your Fears for the Biggest Breakthroughs Were you awkward in eighth grade? I certainly was. It’s no surprise to anyone that knows me that being a dork was my everyday experience. On my face hung big thick-framed nerdy glasses, which were not in style. And I was skinny. Six feet tall, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Learn to</strong> <strong><s>Conquer </s> Redirect Your Fears for the Biggest Breakthroughs</strong></p>



<p>Were you awkward in eighth grade?</p>



<p>I certainly was. It’s no surprise to anyone that knows me that being a dork was my everyday experience. </p>



<p>On my face hung big thick-framed nerdy glasses, which were not in style. </p>



<p>And I was skinny. Six feet tall, yet only a hundred and forty pounds soaking wet. </p>



<p>Because I was tall, I played basketball &#8211; but I wasn’t very good. Coach called me, “the smart player” which I knew wasn’t a compliment.</p>



<p>Fashion sense? I had no idea what that even meant. </p>



<p>I was a teacher’s pet &#8211; I always had the answers the teachers were looking for. I could hear the eye rolls from my classmates every day &#8211; but I wasn&#8217;t deterred. </p>



<p>Being a teacher&#8217;s pet, I was nominated by a teacher for an Outstanding Student award hosted by the local Optimist International Club. And I won!</p>



<p>At first, this was pretty great. I got an award that included a very small savings bond that was to go toward my college expenses.</p>



<p>But then the worst happened…</p>



<p>…they said that I had to give a speech to get the award. And not just in front of my peers &#8211; in front of adults too. </p>



<p>At that point I didn’t want the award &#8211; fear took over my nerdy brain.</p>



<p>“What if I fail? What if I forget what to say? What if I make a fool out of myself?” <br>
All these crazy worst-case scenario thoughts went through my head.</p>



<p>I wanted them to pick someone else as the winner.</p>



<p>As the date for the speech got closer and closer, the fear ratcheted up more and more. I knew that I’d be disappointing my parents and my teachers if I didn’t follow through with the speech. But I hated it more the closer the event approached.</p>



<p>Turns out, I didn’t crash and burn &#8211; but I didn’t do great either. I was nervous: I talked very quietly and too fast, and I wanted it to be over quickly.</p>



<p>Several years later, as a part of a Toastmasters group, I took on the fear of public speaking head-on. </p>



<p>One of the most important things I learned in Toastmasters was to understand what nervousness felt like. And to take that nervousness and redirect it into something positive. The key was NOT to eliminate nerves but to recognize them and channel them into something positive.</p>



<p>That little lesson jumped into my vision again as I read through Marie Forelo’s brilliant book, “Everything is Figureoutable.” In the chapter, “How to Deal With the Fear of Anything,” she writes, “Fear is not the enemy. Waiting to stop feeling afraid is.” </p>



<p>She goes on to give examples of experts that still get a healthy dose of fear before they perform.</p>



<p>But it’s not just fear of speaking &#8211; it is fear of all kinds. I’ve had several people tell me things like, “Oh I could never go into business for myself &#8211; that’s frightening!” The truth is it is scary- so many things could go wrong. But if we fail to act because we’re scared, you’ll never achieve your biggest goals.</p>



<p><strong><em>What are you afraid of? </em></strong></p>



<p><em><strong>What are you telling yourself that you could never do? </strong></em></p>



<p>A healthy dose of fear might just be telling you exactly what you should be doing next.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1278</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Unstuck: A Bias Toward Action</title>
		<link>/get-unstuck-a-bias-toward-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Who are the most productive people you know? Think about their day-to-day actions. Are they prone to getting stuck? Or do they simply crank out work consistently and make it look easy? You can learn from these productivity wizards by adopting the mindset they all have. It’s called, “A Bias Toward Action.” They think, “If [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Who are the most productive people you know? </p>



<p>Think about their day-to-day actions. Are they prone to getting stuck? Or do they simply crank out work consistently and make it look easy?</p>



<p>You can learn from these productivity wizards by adopting the mindset they all have.</p>



<p>It’s called, “A Bias Toward Action.”</p>



<p>They think, “If I’m in doubt, I’m going to act. If I’m stuck, I’m going to act. If I’m (fill in the blank), I’m going to act.”</p>



<p>No matter what, it is time to act.</p>



<p>The most productive people are the ones that don’t wait for everything to align. They don’t need to have all the answers about the future lined up before they start working.</p>



<p>The planets DO NOT need to align for you to do your best work right now. </p>



<p>So many of us (me included!) need to have all the detail sorted out before we put our full effort towards a project. We call it procrastination and we also call it common sense: &#8220;let’s not work on something that might not succeed.&#8221;  But this attitude isn&#8217;t helpful &#8211; it keeps us from moving forward.</p>



<p>When I get stuck on something because I don’t have the details, it feels a bit like I CAN’T move forward. Some call this &#8216;analysis paralysis.&#8217; I can get caught in this mode, especially the more complex a project I’m working on. </p>



<p>But this “paralysis” isn’t helping you &#8211; it’s hindering your progress.</p>



<p>When you’re forging new territory, it’s impossible to have all the details. But more often than not, this is not necessary &#8211; and some ambiguity is good! Gaps in the project allow for creativity and new solutions that you might not have seen. </p>



<p>This is not to say that planning is a bad thing! Planning is excellent and can help you get to where you want to go. Yet, the danger lies in not moving forward until you have all the plan details in place. If you’re doing ground-breaking work, there’s no way you’ll have all the detail on your plan. You should include planning in your project, but don’t let gaps in the plan deter you from taking action today.</p>



<p>Is it your goal to become more productive? Then adopt the mindset that you don’t have to have all the details worked out before you begin.</p>



<p>JUST ACT. Let’s Go!</p>



<p>Get moving and fill in the details along the way! </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1275</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slowing Down to Speed Up</title>
		<link>/slowing-down-to-speed-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How Being Busy Hurts Your Progress “How are you doing?” “Busy &#8211; really busy!”&#160; Have you had a conversation like this recently?&#160; We go from being ridiculously busy during the holidays &#8211; to being super busy at the start of the New Year. We’ve got new resolutions, personal goals, and new work objectives and targets [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>How Being Busy Hurts Your Progress</h4>



<p><em>“How are you doing?”<br><br>“Busy &#8211; really busy!”&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Have you had a conversation like this recently?&nbsp;</p>



<p>We go from being ridiculously busy during the holidays &#8211; to being super busy at the start of the New Year. We’ve got new resolutions, personal goals, and new work objectives and targets to hit. It’s easy to get overwhelmed by it all and feel extremely busy.</p>



<p>Is “busy” what we are striving for? Or is it something else?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Busy does not equal productive. Busy means you are scattered and pushed too thin to be great. You’re bouncing from one thing to the next &#8211; and it feels like you’ll never get off the hamster wheel.</p>



<p>We want to make an impact. We want to do bigger and better work. We want to be more effective.</p>



<p>“Busy” gets in the way of impact, it hinders progress, and it kills effectiveness.</p>



<p>So why do we get that way?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because we tell ourselves that the harder we work, the luckier we get. And this is true &#8211; if, and only if, we are working hard on the essential things.</p>



<p>How do we get to what is essential?&nbsp;</p>



<p>By slowing down. By taking time to think. By being intentional about quieting the noises and distractions around us. By meditating.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those activities are the opposite of busy.</p>



<p>How can adding more things to your to-do list help you become less busy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because when you take the time to slow down and think &#8211; you discover the really important stuff. And you shed the unimportant. The stuff that really matters comes into focus and the other things just blur into the background.</p>



<p>Who do you know that has a New Year’s Resolution to “do all the UN-important stuff?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>What are you doing to be less busy this year? A great way to start is to find yourself some solitude and stillness. Even ten minutes can do amazing things for your well-being.</p>



<p>Be Well,</p>



<p>Ken</p>



<p>P.S. If you’d like to learn more about solitude and stillness, check out Ryan Holiday’s most recent book,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://dailystoic.com/stillness-is-the-key/">Stillness is the Key</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1268</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Assess Your Value</title>
		<link>/how-to-assess-your-value/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week I had an interesting conversation about value. The person I was coaching said, “I didn’t really do anything yesterday &#8211; I was a real piece of s**t.” And something really important clicked for me. There’s a huge difference between your economic value (what you output and give to society) and your inherent value [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This week I had an interesting conversation about value. </p>



<p>The person I was coaching said, “I didn’t really do anything yesterday &#8211; I was a real piece of s**t.” And something really important clicked for me. </p>



<p>There’s a huge difference between your economic value (what you output and give to society) and your inherent value as a human being. </p>



<p>I have been guilty of this for many years and still struggle with it. But a new way of thinking about people and their value can help you be a better human.</p>



<p>We often think of how valuable a person is by their economic value. How much do they make? How advanced is their career? How many things have they accrued? How nice are their cars? </p>



<p>But none of this matters to the inherent value of another human being. </p>



<p>I’ve had to fire people in the past for bringing down a team and not doing the work they were assigned to do. But that absolutely doesn’t mean that the person getting fired was less valuable. Yes, it’s true, they were no longer economically viable to keep on the payroll &#8211; but that fact DOES NOT diminish their value as a human one iota. </p>



<p>You can see it often &#8211; picture the person yelling, “Get a job!” to a homeless person asking for money on the street corner. Their misplaced value of that person says they are less than because they have less than others. </p>



<p>You see it when a person in the workplace is disrespectful to the janitor or the security guard or the delivery person. </p>



<p>Every one &#8211; EVERY PERSON &#8211; has immense value. And even if they can do nothing for you &#8211; that doesn’t diminish it at all. </p>



<p>This mindset shift is important &#8211; it will help you understand to be more compassionate with others. It will help you not be so frustrated the next time the panhandler asks you for money. It will help you transform the way you think about yourself too. </p>



<p>You are not your career &#8211; no matter how successful you are. That didn’t increase your inherent value at all. Sure, your bank account might have more than most people around you, but that does not mean you’re better than any of them.</p>



<p>Even if you’re great to those around you and see the inherent value in every human &#8211; I bet you’re not that way with yourself all the time. </p>



<p>It’s sneaky and insidious &#8211; you feel bad after an unproductive day. You forgot to run an errand &#8211; so you internally call yourself a name. You missed a key deadline at work &#8211; you call yourself a lazy son-of-a-… you get the picture. </p>



<p>You are valuable.<br>Treat yourself as such. </p>



<p>When you separate your economic value from your inherent value, you’ll be transformed into someone you might not even recognize. And others will see it too. </p>



<p>And the big surprise is, when you separate your work output from your value as a human being, you are freed up to get more done and create more economic value.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1265</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remote Work: Is Anybody Watching?</title>
		<link>/remote-work-is-anybody-watching/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 15:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How to keep your career on track while working remotely. Out of all the challenges of working remotely &#8211; working from home, a coffee shop, or other location &#8211; one of the biggest is how do you show your work? Are your results &#8216;seen&#8217; or &#8216;unseen?&#8217;&#160; If you work in a support role, you likely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><em>How to keep your career on track while working remotely.</em></strong></p>



<p>Out of all the challenges of working remotely &#8211; working from home, a coffee shop, or other location &#8211; one of the biggest is how do you show your work?</p>



<p><strong>Are your results &#8216;seen&#8217; or &#8216;unseen?&#8217;&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>If you work in a support role, you likely have results that are &#8216;seen.&#8217; You have a hard count of the number of issues you solved on a given day. These can be good barometers of your work, but some of the least effective workers can close a lot of issues, yet not get much done. How many of those tickets/ issues did you “solve” that had to be re-opened &#8211; and handled by someone else? Or what about that issue that took a lot more time than average &#8211; it might drag your numbers down if you have a few of them in a week. Even with &#8216;seen&#8217; numbers, it isn’t as cut and dry as sharing your numbers. It can be much more than that.</p>



<p>Let’s say you&#8217;re not doing much in the way of support and you have projects that you need to take on. Well, those can be &#8216;seen&#8217; results too &#8211; if the project plan has the list of the deliverables you need to complete, then that is very visible. Drop one or more of those and believe me, someone will &#8216;see&#8217; you &#8211; especially if others can’t do their work until you do your part.<br>But what if your work is more &#8216;unseen?&#8217; Here is a question to know if your work is &#8216;unseen&#8217; &#8211; could you go a day or more and not move anything forward without anyone noticing? I don’t recommend this &#8211; but if that is / or could be true for you then your work is likely &#8216;unseen.&#8217; For example, you might have to deliver a proposal for a new system upgrade in two weeks. You’ve got a lot of research to do to find a solution that fits the requirements and get the project documented. You could skip work on it today and likely have a satisfactory presentation anyways. But you can&#8217;t defer that work forever, or it shows in the quality of your presentation.</p>



<p><strong>My Challenge to You</strong></p>



<p><br>Here’s a challenge for you: no matter if your work is &#8216;seen&#8217; or &#8216;unseen,&#8217; evaluate your work objectively as if YOU were the manager in charge. This is especially important if you want to get promoted &#8211; self-management is essential to your continued success. When you do this, you won’t need a manager. Self-management is one of the most desired attributes of team members. No one wants to be a babysitter, not even your manager. One of the most resonant TV commercials of all time was from Monster.com. “I wanna work my way up to middle management,” one baby shouted with heavy sarcasm. Being in middle management is a lot like babysitting most days. You&#8217;ll shine as a top performer if you don&#8217;t need supervision.</p>



<p>It is amazing how managing your effort and communicating your results is a big difference-maker in your career.<br></p>



<p><strong>You&#8217;re in charge of your own work: take control!&nbsp;<br></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Slowed Down Time with One Weird Experiment</title>
		<link>/how-i-slowed-down-time-with-one-weird-experiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 16:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It&#8217;s only 9:30?&#8221; I said to my wife after a morning full of conversation, reading, and sipping coffee. &#8220;Yes, it is weird, isn&#8217;t it,&#8221; she replied. The oddities persisted all day &#8211; at 1:30, it felt like the sun should be going down shortly. And at 5 pm, it felt like it was more like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>&#8220;<em>It&#8217;s only 9:30?</em>&#8221; I said to my wife after a morning full of conversation, reading, and sipping coffee.</p>



<p>&#8220;<em>Yes, it is weird, isn&#8217;t it</em>,&#8221; she replied.</p>



<p>The oddities persisted all day &#8211; at 1:30, it felt like the sun should be going down shortly. And at 5 pm, it felt like it was more like 8 pm. </p>



<p>It was like time had slowed down. What was different?</p>



<p>Having just finished the book, <em>Digital Minimalism</em> by Cal Newport, I decided to test out his hypothesis that we are all too distracted by our phones, the Internet, and social apps.</p>



<p>I didn&#8217;t feel like I was very distracted by these things &#8211; I thought they probably had a mild effect on me, but they were worth the distraction. I 100% believed that a digital detox wouldn&#8217;t impact me that much- but in the interest of improving my self-awareness, I wanted to give it a try.</p>



<p>So on Friday, I sent a few people I interact with regularly this message: &#8220;<em>FYI &#8211; Tomorrow (Saturday) I&#8217;m going to have a technology-free day: no computers, no cell phones, no internet surfing, no texting.</em>&#8220;</p>



<p>My 20-year-old son, who lives across town, wrote back, &#8220;<em>I shall send smoke signals accompanied by pigeons.</em>&#8221; The smart-ass doesn&#8217;t fall far from the tree.</p>



<p>So while Cal Newport didn&#8217;t expressly prescribe this 24-hour detox (he suggests a more extended period), I wanted some quick information about my current habits.</p>



<p>I was shocked: I was very, very wrong. I was <strong>constantly</strong> distracted by my devices. And those little, seemingly insignificant distractions added up to real time I was wasting.</p>



<p>Cutting out these few things had added an immense amount of time back to my day. You might think that it was boring &#8211; and that&#8217;s why time seemed to slow down, but it wasn&#8217;t at all. It was a productive day, full of reading interesting concepts, getting outside and splitting some firewood, having interesting conversations, and generally feeling much calmer and in control.</p>



<p>The other surprising thing was that only one of us did the experiment, me, and it had positive impacts for both my wife and me. She said, &#8220;<em>It&#8217;s much easier to talk to you today.&#8221;</em> Wow. </p>



<p>I did feel the pull throughout the day to check my texts, my email, and social media accounts. But they weren&#8217;t that hard to resist &#8211; I knew they&#8217;d be there tomorrow and I wouldn&#8217;t miss a thing.</p>



<p><strong>Exceptions:</strong></p>



<p>Before the digital detox began, I had one exception: I am part of a 500 word-a-day writing challenge on the app &#8216;SPAR!&#8217; and I needed to record a check-in video with my word count displayed. I had written over 700 words in my paper notebook earlier in the day. I enlisted the help of my wife to get my phone and open that app  (so I wouldn&#8217;t see anything else), and I quickly recorded the video check-in. This quick check-in allowed me to maintain my near year-long daily writing streak.</p>



<p><strong>The Biggest Challenge:</strong></p>



<p>The biggest (and unexpected!) challenge came about 8pm. My wife and I were watching a TV show when suddenly the power went out, and we were sitting in the dark. We retrieved flashlights, and I wanted to grab my phone to see if the power company had posted an update for restoration. I&#8217;m signed up for text alerts &#8211; but of course, I couldn&#8217;t check my texts. The lack of information made me restless &#8211; I had a hard time maintaining focus on the book I had read effortlessly earlier in the day. I wanted information I knew was out there, but I couldn&#8217;t access it.</p>



<p>The next morning, I woke with the eager anticipation of seeing what gems awaited me on my phone. It was a similar feeling to being a kid waking up on Christmas morning.</p>



<p>However, my excitement was short-lived. I had 14 text messages, about 30 emails, and a couple of social media mentions. I responded to them all in about 15 minutes &#8211; and then it was back to normal.</p>



<p>Really? I trade hours of my day checking these various things &#8211; and it was all distilled into 15 minutes of responses this morning? WOW.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s how I learned to slow down the clock &#8211; put the phone down, keep email and social media closed &#8211; and be more intentional and disciplined about when I check them. </p>



<p>Today has been different &#8211; I&#8217;ve checked my phone, my email, and some key websites, but not nearly as often. I am okay with the tension of waiting &#8211; it will all be there for me when I decide to check.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re like I was, and you think you&#8217;re not affected by these things, try a 24-hour challenge. No phone, no texts, no computers, no surfing. Set your own rules (and exceptions, if needed) and pick a day to try it.</p>



<p>You might be surprised how much time you spend. And learning the discipline of intentionality is powerful. </p>



<p><strong>Remember, you&#8217;re in control of your devices. You get to choose.</strong></p>



<p>I&#8217;d love to hear how it goes. Let me know! Email me at ken@elevaros.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">848</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Keys to Giving Effective Presentations</title>
		<link>/three-keys-to-giving-effective-presentations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wpelevaros]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Understanding Others]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All technologists need presentation skills, whether you’re presenting to one person or to many. As such, here are three tips that I’ve found particularly useful that can help you get your message across. What is the cognitive effect I want my audience to experience? Often times, we forget the audience when we’re developing our presentations. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>All technologists need presentation skills, whether you’re presenting to one person or to many. As such, here are three tips that I’ve found particularly useful that can help you get your message across.</p>



<p><strong>What is the cognitive effect I want my audience to experience?</strong></p>



<p>Often times, we forget the audience when we’re developing our presentations. It is easy to focus on our subject and just dive right into the content — and hope people catch on. But it is helpful to think about the effect you want your presentation to have BEFORE you start building it. </p>



<p>For example, if you were asked to give a talk on a new technology your team is looking to use, your cognitive effect could either be “to get the team excited about it” or “to teach the team to operate it.” Do you see how those would be wildly different presentations on the same subject? </p>



<p>Knowing your intended effect even before creating your presentation is a great strategy. But don’t leave it only as an initial step. Continually review and ensure that your presentation is meeting this important goal throughout the development of your talk.</p>



<p><strong>Get comfortable with silence</strong></p>



<p>I spent a couple of years in a Toastmasters club, and one of the most important takeaways is that silence is a key part of any presentation.</p>



<p>Most new speakers have an aversion to silence, though. After all, the point of a presentation is to talk, right? So we react and try to fill all of the available time with words. </p>



<p>But silence does a lot of important things: 1) it allows your audience to process what you’ve said, 2) it can be leveraged to create tension and drama for an emotional connection, and 3) it shows your audience that you are at ease, even if you feel like vomiting or passing out. </p>



<p><strong>The power of &#8220;Thank You&#8221; and &#8220;I’ll Get Back to You On That&#8221;</strong></p>



<p>One of the most challenging things that can happen during a presentation is when one of your audience members gives you some feedback or asks a challenging question you don’t know the answer to right away.</p>



<p>In the first scenario, if someone speaks up to tell you that you had an error in your presentation — whether or not they are correct — don’t try to argue or defend your point. Just say, “Thank you,” earnestly and sincerely and move on.</p>



<p>Similarly, if an attendee asks you a question that you don’t know the answer to immediately, it’s completely fine in most circumstances to say, “I don’t have that right now, but I’ll get back to you on that.” And after the presentation concludes, follow up with the questioner. This way, you avoid getting derailed and stay in control. But you are also genuinely helpful. None of us knows everything, so it is completely acceptable to say, “I’ll get back to you on that,” and follow through afterward. But danger! Saying you’ll follow up and then never following through is a credibility killer. If you say you will do something, then do everything in your power to do it. I like to have a notebook handy. And as soon as my presentation is over, I write down my takeaways right away so that I don’t forget them later. In other words, do what works for you.</p>



<p>Practice these the next time you give a presentation, and I’m sure you’ll get your message across more effectively.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">846</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
